Dutch Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Dutch Painting Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 22
Yale University Arts Library
177.6
74 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Dutch paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders. Photograph labels use the superseded terminology, Painting - Holland
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized by individual artist name. The individual artist material is further divided primarily by location of work. The individual artist portion is preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Dutch paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders. Photograph labels use the superseded terminology, Painting - Holland
Painting, Dutch; Painting -- Netherlands; Photographs; Reproductions
- Anonymous. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings of Dutch art, most of it not anonymous.
  - Unnamed and undated photographs., 3 (Box 1)
  - XV Century., 20 (Box 1)
  - XVI Century., 6 (Box 1)
  - XVII Century., 12 (Box 1)
  - XVIII Century., 2 (Box 1)
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
- A
  - Miscellaneous Artists A., 7 (Box 1)
    - Aken, Jan van, 1614-1661 (?)., 1 (Box 1)
    - Amstel, Jan Aertson van, 1500-1540., 2 (Box 1)
    - Andriessen, Jurriaan, 1742-1819., 1 (Box 1)
    - Antum, Aert van, active 1630-1640., 1 (Box 1)
    - Assteyn, Bartholomeus, 1607-c.1667., 2 (Box 1)
    - Augustini, Jan, 1725-1773., 1 (Box 1)
  - Individual Artists A., 113
    - Aarts, Johan Joseph, 1871-1934., 4 (Box 1)
    - Aelst, Willem van, c.1625-1683., 5 (Box 1)
    - Aertsen, Peter, 1508-1575., 16 (Box 2)
    - Appel, Karel, 1921-., 35 (Box 2)
    - Arentsz, Arent, 1585-1635., 5 (Box 2)
    - Asselyn, Jan, 1610-1660., 11 (Box 2)
    - Ast, Balthasar van der, 1590-1656., 9 (Box 3)
    - Avercamp, Hendrik, 1585-1663., 28 (Box 3)
- B
  - Miscellaneous Artists B., 60
    - Baburen, Dirck van, active 1611-1623., 4 (Box 3)
    - Backer, Adriaen, 1635-1684., 1 (Box 4)
    - Baen, Jan de, 1633-1702., 2 (Box 4)
    - Bailly, David, 1584-c.1657., 2 (Box 4)
    - Bakhuijzen, Julius-Jacobus van de Sande, 1835-post 1880., 1 (Box 4)
    - Banck, Jan van der, -1739., 1 (Box 4)
    - Barendsz, Dirck, 1534-1592., 3 (Box 4)
      Artist's name also spelled "Barentsz."
    - Bassan, Bartholomeus van, 1590-1652., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bauer, Maurice Alexandre, XX Century., 1 (Box 4)
    - Beelt, Cornelis, XVII Century., 2 (Box 4)
    - Beerstraten, A., active 1658-1668., 1 (Box 4)
    - Beerstraten, Jan A., 1622-1666., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bega, Cornelis, 1620-1664., 1 (Box 4)
    - Benner, Gerrit, XX Century., 2 (Box 4)
    - Berckheyde, Job. Andriaensz, 1630-1693., 2 (Box 4)
    - Beyer, Jan de, 1703-1750 (?)., 1 (Box 4)
    - Blieck, Daniel de, -1673., 1 (Box 4)
    - Blocklandt, Anthonie van, 1532-1583., 2 (Box 4)
    - Bloemaert, Hendrik I, 1601-1672., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bock, Theophile E. A. de, 1851-1904., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bor, Paulus, 1600-1669., 2 (Box 4)
    - Borman, Johannes, active 1653-1658., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bosschaert, Abraham, 1613-1643., 1 (Box 4)
    - Both, Andreas, 1608-1641., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bouckhorst, Jan van, active 1617-1631., 3 (Box 4)
    - Brakenburgh, R., 1650-1702., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bray, Dirck de, active 1651-1678., 1 (Box 4)
    - Breen, Adam van, active 1612-1629., 3 (Box 4)
    - Breenbergh, Bartholomeus, 1599-1659., 1 (Box 4)
    - Breitner, Georg Hendrik, 1857-1923., 2 (Box 4)
    - Brekelenkam, Quiryn van, 1620-1658., 5 (Box 4)
    - Bremmer, Hendrik P., 1871-1956., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bronckhorst, Jan Gerritsz van, 1603-1661., 1 (Box 4)
    - Burgh, Hendrck van der, active 1650-1670., 5 (Box 4)
    - Bylert, Jan van, 1603-1671., 1 (Box 4)
  - Individual Artists B., 239
    - Backer, Jacob Adriaensz, 1608-1651., 5 (Box 4)
    - Backhuysen, Ludolf, 1631-1701., 8 (Box 4)
    - Berchem, Nicholas, 1620-1683., 28 (Box 4)
    - Berckheyde, Gerrit, 1630-1698., 15 (Box 4)
    - Beyeren, Abraham van, 1620-1674., 25 (Box 4)
    - Bloemaert, Abraham, 1564-1651., 43 (Box 5)
      - Drawings., 18 (Box 5)
      - Paintings., 25 (Box 5)
    - Bol, Ferdinand, 1616-1680., 36 (Box 5)
    - Borssom, Anthony van, c.1629/30-1677., 4 (Box 5)
    - Bosboom, Johannes, 1817-1891., 4 (Box 5)
    - Bosschaert, Ambrosius, active 1588-1640., 6 (Box 6)
    - Both, Jan, 1618-1652., 18 (Box 6)
    - Boursse, Esias, 1631-1672., 4 (Box 6)
    - Bramer, Leonard, 1596-1674., 4 (Box 6)
    - Bray, Jan de, 1627-1697., 21 (Box 6)
    - Bray, Salomon de, 1597-1664., 3 (Box 6)
    - Breenbergh, Bartholomeus, 1599-1659., 7 (Box 6)
    - Buytenwech, Willem, 1585-1627., 8 (Box 7)
- C
  - Miscellaneous Artists C., 19 (Box 7)
    - Calcar, Johan Stephan van, 1499-1546., 1 (Box 7)
    - Calcar, Jan Joest van, 1460-1519., 2 (Box 7)
    - Calvaert, Denys, 1540-1619., 1 (Box 7)
    - Camphuijsen, Govert, 1623/4-1672., 1 (Box 7)
    - Carree, Michiel, 1657-1727., 1 (Box 7)
    - Cats, Jacob, 1741-1799., 1 (Box 7)
    - Ceulen, Cornelis Janssens van, 1593-1661., 1 (Box 7)
    - Cleve, Cornelis van, active 1540-1554., 1 (Box 7)
    - Colyer, Edwaert (Everett), active 1662-1700., 1 (Box 7)
    - Compe, Jan ten, 1713-1761., 3 (Box 7)
    - Coorte, Adriaen S., active 1683-1707., 1 (Box 7)
    - Crabeth, Dirk, -1577., 1 (Box 7)
    - Cronenburgh, Andriaen van, active 1500-1567., 1 (Box 7)
    - Croos, Anthony Jan van der, 1606-1663., 2 (Box 7)
    - Cuylenborch, Abraham van, active 1639-1658., 1 (Box 7)
  - Individual Artists C., 195
    - Capelle, Jan van de, 1624-1679., 21 (Box 7)
    - Claesz, Pieter, 1597-1661., 16 (Box 7)
    - Codde, Pieter Jacobsz and Lucas, 1599-1678., 4 (Box 7)
    - Corneille, 1922-., 10 (Box 7)
      Artist's full name: Corneille Guillaume van Beverloo.
    - Cornelis, Van Haarlem, 1562-1638., 18 (Box 8)
    - Cornelisz, Jacob van Amsterdam, 1470-1533., 49 (Box 8)
    - Cuyp, Aelbert, 1620-1691., 64
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 8)
      - Paintings., 59 (Box 9)
    - Cuyp, Benjamin, 1612-1652., 6 (Box 9)
    - Cuyp, Jacob Gerritsz, 1594-1652., 7 (Box 10)
- D
  - Miscellaneous Artists D., 26 (Box 10)
    - Danckerts, Johan, 1615-1681/87., 1 (Box 10)
    - de Fries, Roelof, active 1643-1669., 1 (Box 10)
    - Delen, Dirck van, 1605-1671., 4 (Box 10)
    - de Lust, A., XVII Century., 1 (Box 10)
    - de Man, Cornelis, 1621-1706., 1 (Box 10)
    - Dibbets, Jan, 1941-., 2 (Box 10)
    - Diederen, Jef, 1920-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Dijck, Floris Claesz van, 1575-1651., 2 (Box 10)
    - Dircksz, Barend, ?., 1 (Box 10)
    - Donck, Gerard, active 1627-1640., 1 (Box 10)
    - Drayer, Reinder Juurt, 1899-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Droochsloot, Joost Cornelisz, 1586-1666., 2 (Box 10)
      Artists's name also spelled "Droogsloot."
    - Drost, Willem, 1630-1687., 4 (Box 10)
    - Duck, Jacob, 1600-1660., 3 (Box 10)
    - Dyck, Abraham van, 1636-1672., 1 (Box 10)
  - Individual Artists D., 145
    - Doesburg, Theo van, 1883-1931., 18 (Box 10)
    - Dongen, Kees van, 1877-1968., 54 (Box 11)
    - Doomer, Lambert, 1622/3-1700., 7 (Box 11)
    - Dou, Gerard, 1613-1675., 42
      - individual locations, 29
        - Amsterdam., 6 (Box 11)
        - Dresden., 6 (Box 11)
        - London., 5 (Box 11)
        - New York., 3 (Box 11)
        - Paris., 4 (Box 12)
        - Rotterdam., 2 (Box 12)
        - Washington D.C., 3 (Box 12)
    - Dujardin, Karel, 1622-1678., 13 (Box 12)
    - Dusart, Cornelis, 1660-1704., 6 (Box 12)
    - Duyster, Willem Cornelisz, 1599-1635., 5 (Box 12)
- E
  - Miscellaneous Artists E., 8 (Box 12)
    - Eeckhout, Albert, 1604-1666., 1 (Box 12)
    - Elias, Nicolaes, 1588/91-1646/56., 2 (Box 12)
    - Escher, M. C., 1898-1972., 1 (Box 12)
    - Everdingen, Caesar Boethius van, 1606-1678., 4 (Box 12)
  - Individual Artists E., 27
    - Eeckhout, Gerbrand van den, 1621-1674., 9 (Box 12)
    - Engelbrechtsz, Cornelis, c.1468-1533., 7 (Box 12)
    - Everdingen, Allaert van, 1621-1675., 16 (Box 12)
      Artist's name also spelled "Albert" and "Allart."
    - Eworth, Hans, active 1540-1574., 5 (Box 13)
- F (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Artists F., 4 (Box 13)
    Includes a file of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Fargue, Jacob Elias la, 1734-after 1776., 1 (Box 13)
    - Francken, Frans II, 1581-1642., 1 (Box 13)
    - Fernhout, Edgar, 1912-., 1 (Box 13)
    - Furnerius, Abraham, 1628-1654., 1 (Box 13)
  - Individual Artists F., 51 (Box 13)
    - Fabritius, Barent, 1624-1673., 10 (Box 13)
    - Fabritius, Carel, 1622-1654., 20 (Box 13)
    - Flinck, Govaert, 1615-1660., 21 (Box 13)
- G
  - Miscellaneous Artists G., 14 (Box 13)
    - Gabriel, Paul Josphus Constantin, 1828-1903., 2 (Box 13)
    - Gael, Barend, 1630/40-after 1681., 2 (Box 13)
    - Geel, Jacob Jacobz van, 1585-1638., 1 (Box 13)
    - Geest, Wybrand the Elder, 1590/2-1659., 1 (Box 13)
    - Gorter, Arnold-Marc, 1866-1933., 1 (Box 13)
    - Graat, Barend, 1628-1709., 1 (Box 13)
    - Grebber, Pieter Fransz de, 1600-1652., 3 (Box 13)
    - Griffier, Jan the Elder, 1652-1718., 2 (Box 13)
    - Griffier, Jan the Younger, -1750., 1 (Box 13)
  - Individual Artists G., 150
    - Geertgen, tot St. Jans, active 1465-1593., 27 (Box 14)
    - Gelder, Aert de, 1645-1727., 11 (Box 14)
    - Gheyn, Jacques de, the Elder, 1530-1582, the Younger, 1565-1629., 17 (Box 14)
    - Goltzius,Hendrick, 1558-1617., 20
      - Drawings., 12 (Box 14)
      - Paintings., 8 (Box 15)
    - Goyen, Jan van, 1596-1656., 75 (Box 15)
      - Drawings., 12 (Box 15)
      - Paintings., 63 (Box 15)
- H
  - Miscellaneous Artists H., 23 (Box 16)
    - Hackaert, Jan, 1629-1700., 2 (Box 16)
    - Hals, Harmen, 1611-1669., 1 (Box 16)
    - Hardenstein, Dirk, 1620-., 1 (Box 16)
    - Heda, Gerrit Willemsz, active 1642-1702., 2 (Box 16)
    - Heem, David Davidsz de, active 1668., 1 (Box 16)
    - Hemessen, Jan van, active 1500-1566., 1 (Box 16)
    - Hendricks, Wybrand, 1744-1831., 1 (Box 16)
    - Hoet, Gerard, 1648-1733., 2 (Box 16)
    - Hogers, Jacob, 1614-1641., 1 (Box 16)
    - Hondius, Abraham, 1630-1691., 2 (Box 16)
    - Hondius, Hendrick, 1573-1650., 1 (Box 16)
    - Horst, Gerrit Williams, 1612-1652., 1 (Box 16)
    - Hosteyn, Cormelis, 1618-1658., 1 (Box 16)
    - Houckgeest, Gerard, 1600-1660., 1 (Box 16)
    - Houckgeest, Joachim, 1580-1644., 1 (Box 16)
    - Houten, Gerrit van, XX Century., 1 (Box 16)
    - Huchtenburgh, Jan van, 1648-1733., 1 (Box 16)
    - Huyghens, Constatijn, ?., 1 (Box 16)
    - Hynckes, Raoul, 1893-., 1 (Box 16)
  - Individual Artists H., 657
    - Haan, Meyer de, 1852-1895., 4 (Box 16)
    - Hals, Dirk, 1591-1656., 10 (Box 16)
    - Hals, Frans, 1590-1666., 263 (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous collections., 77 (Box 17)
      - Amsterdam., 22 (Box 18)
      - Berlin., 12 (Box 18)
      - Brussels., 4 (Box 18)
      - Cassel., 9 (Box 18)
      - Haarlem., 52 (Box 19)
        - Individuals., 6 (Box 19)
        - Governors of the Old Men's Home at Haarlem., 14 (Box 19)
        - Lady Governors of the Old Mens Home at Haarlem., 15 (Box 19)
        - Governors of S. Elisabeth's Hospital at Haarlem., 5 (Box 19)
        - Officers of the Civic Guard of S. Adrian at Haarlem., 6 (Box 19)
        - Officers of the Civic Guard of S. George at Haarlem., 6 (Box 19)
      - London., 12 (Box 20)
      - New Haven., 18 (Box 20)
      - New York., 27 (Box 20)
      - Paris., 12 (Box 20)
      - Washington., 18 (Box 21)
    - Hanneman, Adriaen, 1600-1671., 7 (Box 21)
    - Heda, Willem Claesz, 1594-1682., 10 (Box 21)
    - Heem, Cornelius de, 1631-1695., 9 (Box 21)
    - Heem, Jan Davidsz de, 1606-1684., 20 (Box 21)
    - Heemskerck, Martin van, 1498-1574., 51 (Box 21)
      - Drawings., 11 (Box 21)
      - Paintings., 40 (Box 22)
    - Helst, Bartholomues van der, 1611-1670., 21 (Box 22)
    - Heyden, Jan van der, 1637-1712., 21 (Box 22)
    - Hobbema, Meindert, 1638-1709., 64 (Box 23)
    - Hondecoeter family., 22 (Box 24)
      - Hondecoeter, Gilles d', -1638., 2 (Box 24)
      - Hondecoeter, Gyjsbert Gillisz de, 1604-1653., 2 (Box 24)
      - Hondecoeter, Melchior, 1636-1695., 18 (Box 24)
    - Honthorst, Gerard, 1590-1656., 39 (Box 24)
    - Hooch, Pieter de, 1630-1677., 82 (Box 24)
      - Location unlisted., 14 (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 25)
      - Amsterdam., 11 (Box 25)
      - Berlin., 5 (Box 25)
      - London., 17 (Box 25)
      - Paris., 4 (Box 25)
      - Washington., 9 (Box 26)
    - Hoogstraten, Samuel van, 1627-1678., 12 (Box 26)
    - Huysmun, Jan van, 1682-1749., 22 (Box 26)
- I (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous Artists I., 3 (Box 26)
    - Isaacsz, Pieter, 1569-1625., 1 (Box 26)
    - Israels, Isaac, 1865-1934., 2 (Box 26)
  - Individual Artists I., 22 (Box 26)
    - Israels, Josef, 1824-1911., 22 (Box 26)
- J (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous Artists J., 6 (Box 27)
    - Jansz, Frans, active 1523-1527., 1 (Box 27)
    - Jardin, Karel du, c.1622-1678., 1 (Box 27)
    - Jelgerhuis, Johannes, 1770-1836., 1 (Box 27)
    - Jonge, Jan Ekels de, XVIII Century., 1 (Box 27)
    - Jonge, Willem van de Velde de, 1633-1707., 1 (Box 27)
    - Jorn, Asger, 1914-., 1 (Box 27)
  - Individual Artists J., 78 (Box 27)
    - Jannsens, Peter Elinga, 1612-1672., 3 (Box 27)
    - Johnson, Cornelius, 1593-1662., 8 (Box 27)
    - Jongh, Ludolf de, 1616-1679., 5 (Box 27)
    - Jongkind, Johan Barthold, 1819-1891., 62 (Box 27)
- K
  - Miscellaneous Artists K., 28 (Box 28)
    - Kaemmerer, F. H., 1839-1902., 1 (Box 28)
    - Kalraet, Abraham van, 1643-1699., 1 (Box 28)
    - Kamerlingh Onnes, H. H., 1893-., 1 (Box 28)
    - Kater, Arie, 1922-., 1 (Box 28)
    - Keirincx, Alexander, 1600-1652., 1 (Box 28)
    - Kessel, Jan van, 1626-1679., 2 (Box 28)
    - Kessel, Jan van III, 1641-1680., 3 (Box 28)
    - Keun, Hendrik, 1738-1788., 1 (Box 28)
    - Key, Adrian Thomas, c. 1544-c.1589., 1 (Box 28)
    - Kleyn, Pieter Rudolph, 1785-1816., 1 (Box 28)
    - Klomp, Albert Jansen, c.1618-1688., 2 (Box 28)
    - Knijff, Leendert, 1650-1721., 1 (Box 28)
    - Knupfer, Nicolaes, c.1603-1660., 2 (Box 28)
    - Koch, Pyke, 1901-., 4 (Box 28)
    - Koedyck, Isaac, 1616-1668/77., 1 (Box 28)
    - Koekkoek, Hermanus, 1815-1882., 2 (Box 28)
    - Koekkoek, Willem, 1839-1895., 1 (Box 28)
    - Krausz, Simon A., 1760-1825., 1 (Box 28)
    - Kunst, Pieter Cornelisz, c.1484-1560., 1 (Box 28)
  - Individual Artists K., 76
    - Kalff, Willem, 1621-1693., 18 (Box 28)
    - Ketel, Cornelis, 1548-1616., 6 (Box 28)
    - Keyser, Thomas de, 1596-1667., 13 (Box 28)
    - Koekkoek, Barend Cornelius, 1803-1862., 12 (Box 28)
    - Koninck, Philips, 1619-1688., 21 (Box 29)
    - Koninck, Salomon de, 1609-1668., 6 (Box 29)
- L
  - Miscellaneous Artists L., 12 (Box 29)
    - Lachtropius, Nicolaes, active 1656-1700., 1 (Box 29)
    - Leck, Bart van der, 1876-1958., 1 (Box 29)
    - Leupenius, Johan, 1647/48-1693., 2 (Box 29)
    - Levecq, Jacobus, 1634-1675., 1 (Box 29)
    - Leyden, Aertgen van, 1498-1564., 1 (Box 29)
    - Leyden, Lucas Huyghens van, 1494-1533., 1 (Box 29)
    - Linde, Adriaen van der, active 1595-d.1609., 1 (Box 29)
    - Looy, Jacobus van, 1855-1930., 1 (Box 29)
    - Lubbers, Adriaan, 1892-., 1 (Box 29)
    - Luik, XV Century., 1 (Box 29)
    - Lundens, Gerrit, 1682-aft. 1683., 1 (Box 29)
  - Individual Artists L., 117 (Box 29)
    - Lairesse, Gerard de, 1640-1711., 5 (Box 29)
    - Langendijk, Dirk, 1748-1805, and Langendijk, Jan Anthony, 1780-1818., 9 (Box 29)
    - Lastman, Pieter, 1583-1633., 9 (Box 29)
    - Lataster, Gerard, 1920-., 3 (Box 29)
    - Leyster, Judith, 1610-1660., 15 (Box 30)
    - Lievens, Jan, 1607-1674., 16 (Box 30)
    - Lingelbach, Johannes, 1622-1674., 4 (Box 30)
    - Loo, Jacob van, 1614-1670., 2 (Box 30)
    - Lucas van Leyden, 1494-1533., 46 (Box 30)
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 30)
      - Paintings., 40 (Box 30)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 23 (Box 30)
        - Individual locations., 17 (Box 30)
          - Berlin., 8 (Box 30)
          - Boston., 5 (Box 31)
          - Leiden., 4 (Box 31)
    - Lucebert, 1924-., 8 (Box 31)
- M
  - Miscellaneous Artists M., 33 (Box 31)
    - Man, Cornelis, 1621-1706., 2 (Box 31)
    - Mancadan, Jacobus Sibrandi, 1602-1680., 2 (Box 31)
    - Martens, Wilhelm Johannes, 1838-1895., 2 (Box 31)
    - Matham, Jacob, 1571-1631., 1 (Box 31)
    - Meer, Barent van der, 1659-1690/1702., 2 (Box 31)
    - Mesdag, Hendrik W., 1831-1915., 1 (Box 31)
    - Mieris, Jan van, 1660-1690., 1 (Box 31)
    - Mieris, Willem van, 1662-1747., 3 (Box 31)
    - Mignon, Ambrose, 1640-1679., 1 (Box 31)
    - Mijn, George van der, 1723-1763., 1 (Box 31)
    - Moeyaert, Claes Cornelisz, 1600-1669., 1 (Box 31)
    - Moeyaert, Nicolaes, 1592-1655., 1 (Box 31)
    - Mogendorff, Ro, 1907-., 1 (Box 31)
    - Moillon, Louise, 1610-1696., 1 (Box 31)
    - Moritz, Louis, 1773-1850., 1 (Box 31)
    - Moucheron, Frederik de, 1633-1686., 1 (Box 31)
    - Moucheron, Isaac de, 1667-1744., 1 (Box 31)
    - Muller, Jan Harmenz, 1571-1628., 3 (Box 31)
    - Musscher, Michiel van, 1645-1705., 1 (Box 31)
    - Mytens, Daniel the Elder, 1590-1648., 2 (Box 31)
    - Mytens, Daniel, 1644-1688., 2 (Box 31)
    - Mytens, Jan, 1614-1670., 1 (Box 31)
    - Mytens, Martin van, 1695-1770., 1 (Box 31)
  - Individual Artists M., 350 (Box 31)
    - Maes, Nicolaes, 1632-1693., 62 (Box 31)
      - Drawings., 2 (Box 31)
      - Paintings., 60 (Box 32)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 24 (Box 32)
        - Amsterdam., 9 (Box 32)
        - Berlin., 2 (Box 32)
        - Haarlem., 5 (Box 32)
        - London., 13 (Box 32)
        - New York., 7 (Box 32)
    - Maris, Jacob, 1837-1899., 17 (Box 32)
      Some photos have "James Maris" as artist, but it seems to be the same person.
    - Maris, Matthew, 1839-1917., 8 (Box 33)
    - Maris, Willem, 1844-1910., 7 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous Masters., 12 (Box 33)
      - Leiden Master, c.1500., 1 (Box 33)
      - Master of Delft., 1 (Box 33)
      - Master of the Amsterdam Death of the Virgin., 2 (Box 33)
      - Master of the Death of Absalom, active c.1510., 1 (Box 33)
      - Master of the Gathering of the Manna, c.1470., 3 (Box 33)
      - Master of the Johannes Altar, XV Century., 4 (Box 33)
        Also called "Master of the Johannes Panels."
    - Master of the Alkmaar, active c.1500-1525., 12 (Box 33)
    - Master of the Brunswick Diptych, active 1490., 7 (Box 33)
    - Master of the Morrison Triptych, XVI Century., 4 (Box 33)
    - Master of the Virgo Inter Virgins, 1450-1510., 15 (Box 33)
    - Mauve, Anton, 1838-1888., 10 (Box 34)
    - Meegeren, Hans van 1889-1947., 7 (Box 34)
    - Metsu, Gabriel, 1629-1667., 42 (Box 34)
    - Miereveldt, Michiel, 1567-1641., 15 (Box 34)
    - Mieris, Jan van the Elder, 1635-1681., 14 (Box 35)
    - Molenaer, Jan Miense, 1610-1668., 14 (Box 35)
    - Molijn, Pieter, 1595-1661., 6 (Box 35)
    - Mondrian, Piet, 1872-1944., 70 (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 39 (Box 35)
      - Individual locations., 31 (Box 35)
        - The Hague., 6 (Box 35)
        - New Haven., 6 (Box 35)
        - New York., 10 (Box 36)
        - Otterlo., 4 (Box 36)
        - Pittsburgh., 5 (Box 36)
    - Moreelse, Paul, 1571-1638., 12 (Box 36)
    - Mostaert, Jan, 1474-1555., 19 (Box 36)
- N (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous Artists N., 11 (Box 36)
    - Nagel, Jan, -1616., 1 (Box 36)
    - Nanninga, Jaap, 1904-., 1 (Box 36)
    - Nason, Pieter, 1612-c.1690., 2 (Box 36)
    - Neuhuys, Albert, 1844-1914., 1 (Box 36)
    - Nikkelen, Isaak van, 1640-1703., 1 (Box 36)
    - Noordt, Jan van, c.1620-after 1675., 2 (Box 36)
    - Nuyen, Wynand Jan Joseph, 1813-1839., 2 (Box 36)
  - Individual Artists N., 23 (Box 37)
    - Neer, Eglon-Hendrick van der, 1635-1703., 3 (Box 37)
    - Netscher, Caspar, 1639-1684., 20 (Box 37)
- O (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous Artists O., 7 (Box 37)
    - Oepts, Willem, 1904-., 1 (Box 37)
    - Olis, Jan, 1610-1676., 1 (Box 37)
    - Oosterhoudt, Thierry van, 1756-1830., 1 (Box 37)
    - Oosterwyck, Maria, 1630-1693., 1 (Box 37)
    - Ortkens van Nijmegen, Aerdt, c.1470-c.1540., 1 (Box 37)
    - Ouwater, Isaac, 1750-1793., 1 (Box 37)
    - Overbeek, Michiel van, active c.1650-1680., 1 (Box 37)
  - Individual Artists O., 85
    - Ochtervelt, Jacob, 1634-1682., 6 (Box 37)
    - Os, Jan van, 1744-1808., 8 (Box 38)
    - Ostade, Adriaen van, 1610-1685., 50 (Box 38)
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 38)
      - Paintings., 44 (Box 38)
    - Ostade, Isaac van, 1621-1649., 18 (Box 38)
    - Ouwater, Albert van, active 1455-1467., 3 (Box 39)
- P (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous Artists P., 19 (Box 39)
    - Palamedesz, Anthonie, c.1600-1673., 1 (Box 39)
    - Palamedesz, Palamedes, I, 1607-1638., 1 (Box 39)
    - Passe, Crispyn van de, I, 1564-1637., 1 (Box 39)
    - Peeters, Clara, c.1594-1659., 1 (Box 39)
    - Perkois, Jacobus, 1756-1804, 1 (Box 39)
    - Perlmutter, Izsak, 1866-1932., 1 (Box 39)
    - Pieneman, Jan Willem, 1779-1853., 1 (Box 39)
    - Pietersz, Aert, 1650-1612., 1 (Box 39)
    - Pitloo, Anthony Sminck, 1791-1837., 1 (Box 39)
    - Poggenbeek, George, 1853-1903., 1 (Box 39)
    - Porcellis, Jan, 1580-1632., 2 (Box 39)
    - Pothast, Bernard, 1882-1966., 1 (Box 39)
    - Potter, Pieter, 1599-1652., 1 (Box 39)
    - Prins, Johannes N., 1757-1806., 2 (Box 39)
    - Pronck, Cornelis, 1691-1759., 1 (Box 39)
    - Punder, Jacobus de, c.1527-after 1572., 2 (Box 39)
  - Individual Artists P., 67 (Box 39)
    - Pickenoy, Nicolaes E., 1590/1-1653/6., 3 (Box 39)
    - Poelenburg, Cornelis van, 1586-1667., 12 (Box 39)
    - Poorter, Willem de, 1608-after 1648., 3 (Box 39)
    - Post, Frans, 1612-1680., 6 (Box 39)
    - Pot, Hendrik Gerritsz, 1585-1657., 10 (Box 39)
    - Potter, Paulus, 1625-1654., 24 (Box 39)
    - Pynacker, Adam, 1662-1673., 5 (Box 39)
    - Pynas, Jacob, 1590-1648., 4 (Box 40)
- Q (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous Artists Q., 1 (Box 40)
    - Quast, Pieter Janz., 1606-1647., 1 (Box 40)
- R (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous Artists R., 11 (Box 40)
    - Rademaker, Abraham, 1675-1735., 1 (Box 40)
    - Ring, Pieter de, 1615-1660., 2 (Box 40)
    - Robertson, Suze, 1855-1922., 1 (Box 40)
    - Rochussen, Charles, 1814-1894., 1 (Box 40)
    - Roghman, Roelant, 1597-1686., 3 (Box 40)
    - Rooskons, Anton, 1906-., 1 (Box 40)
    - Rottenhammer, Johann, 1564-1625., 1 (Box 40)
    - Ryckaert, Marten, 1587-1631., 1 (Box 40)
  - Individual Artists R., 1195 (Box 40)
    - Ravestyn, Jan Anthonisz van, 1572-1657., 11 (Box 40)
    - Rembrandt van Rijn, 1606-1669., 962 (Box 40)
      Includes a large folder of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Drawings., 174 (Box 41)
        Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings of drawings.
        - Miscellaneous locations., 68 (Box 41)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 28 (Box 41)
          - Landscapes/City views., 11 (Box 41)
          - Portraits., 15 (Box 41)
          - Religious themes., 14 (Box 41)
        - Places A-Z., 25 (Box 42)
        - Amsterdam., 11 (Box 42)
        - Bayonne., 2 (Box 42)
        - Chatsworth., 11 (Box 42)
        - Chicago., 5 (Box 42)
        - London., 8 (Box 42)
        - New York., 23 (Box 42)
        - Paris., 8 (Box 43)
        - Rotterdam., 5 (Box 43)
        - Washington, D.C., 8 (Box 43)
      - Paintings., 805
        - Miscellaneous locations., 23 (Box 43)
        - Places A-M., 36 (Box 43)
        - Places N-Z., 28 (Box 44)
        - Amsterdam., 67 (Box 44)
          - Miscellaneous locations in Amsterdam., 4 (Box 44)
          - Rijksmuseum., 63
            - Miscellaneous subjects., 16 (Box 44)
            - The Night Watch., 15 (Box 44)
            - Portraits and self-portraits., 19 (Box 44)